Preliminary Guide to the Laura "Tibbie" Roberts papers, 1811-2011 and undated RL.01100
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Laura "Tibbie" Roberts papers
1811-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roberts, Laura (Tibbie), 1914-
RL.01100
4.5 Linear Feet
Laura "Tibbie" Roberts is a life-long activist for women's rights and has been repeatedly honored for her community service and volunteering in North Carolina and abroad. The collection consists of correspondence, conference materials, awards, newspaper clippings, and other ephemera from the life and volunteering of Tibbie Roberts. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
2933 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2009 (2009-0084), 3.6 lin. ft.
Gift, 2009 (2009-0150), 0.6 lin. ft.
Gift, 2010 (2010-0131), 0.1 lin. ft.
Gift, 2011 (2011-0108 and 2011-0123), 0.2 lin. ft.
Biographical / Historical Note
Laura "Tibbie" Roberts is a life-long activist for women's rights and has been repeatedly honored for her community service and volunteering in North Carolina and abroad.
Collection Overview
The accession (2009-0084) (3.6 lin. ft.; 2700 items; dated 1970s-2000s) consists of correspondence, conference materials, awards, newspaper clippings, and other ephemera from the life and volunteering of Tibbie Roberts. Items of note include her materials from the North Carolina Council of Churches, the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women in Beijing (1995), North Carolina Council for Women, the National Women's Conference in Houston (1978), and the United Methodist Church's United Methodist Women Southeast Jurisdiction. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
The accession (2009-0150) (0.6 lin. ft.; 200 items; dated 1970s-1995) consists largely of scrapbooks from Roberts' conferences in the 1990s, including her trips to China, Singapore, and Malaysia as part of the Fourth Annual World Conference on Women, the NGO Forum on Women, and the World Methodist Conference, and her trip to Israel as part of an excavation course. Also included are materials from a filmstrip promoting the Equal Rights Amendment.
Accession (2010-0131) (0.1 lin. ft.; 25 items; dated 1979-1997 and undated) comprises material primarily related to support for the Equal Rigths Amendment. Includes printed material, newspaper clippings, 15 color photographs, and an ERA necklace medalion.
Accession (2011-0108 and 2011-0123)(0.2 lin. ft.; 8 items; dated 1811-2011 and undated) includes a family deed regarding land in Craven County; a letter; printed items on women and religion, one of which is annotated by the donor; and a piece of ephemera with a quote from the ERA on the front and a Bible verse on the back.
Equal rights amendment; Equal rights amendments -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Morehead City (N.C.) -- Volunteers; Photographs; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; North Carolina Council of Churches Equal Rights Committee; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; United Methodist Women -- North Carolina; Roberts, Laura (Tibbie), 1914-; Roberts, Laura (Tibbie), 1914-
- Accession (2009-0084), 1970s-2008, 6 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The accession (2009-0084) (3.6 lin. ft.; 2700 items; dated 1970s-2000s) consists of correspondence, conference materials, awards, newspaper clippings, and other ephemera from the life and volunteering of Tibbie Roberts. Items of note include her materials from the North Carolina Council of Churches, the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women in Beijing (1995), North Carolina Council for Women, the National Women's Conference in Houston (1978), and the United Methodist Church's United Methodist Women Southeast Jurisdiction.
  - Newsclippings, 1970s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Appointment calendar, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Equal Rights Committee (Box 1)
  - Religious Network for Equality for Women (RNEW) (Box 1)
  - NC Council of Churches
    - Equal Rights Committee Conferences on Women, Faith, and Justice (Box 1)
    - Equal Rights Committee minutes, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
  - NC Council for Women (Box 1)
  - NC Women's Forum (Box 1)
  - Morehead City N.C. materials and programs, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
  - Newsclippings, Morehead City N.C. (Box 1)
  - Plaques (Box 2)
  - Awards (Box 2)
  - Awards-related correspondence, 1980s-2000s (Box 2)
  - Beijing travel souvenir book, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Materials from the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Travel itinerary (Box 3)
    - Conference files (Box 3)
    - Newsclippings (Box 3)
    - Photographs (Box 3)
    - Editorials (Box 3)
  - Printed materials
    - By Her Own Bootstraps, Albert Coates (Box 3)
    - Theologies Written from Feminist Perspectives (Box 3)
    - Women's America: Refocusing the Past (Box 3)
    - Women Men and the Bible (Box 3)
    - Speaking for Children (Box 3)
  - NCC ERA miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - ERA handouts (Box 4)
  - Status ERA Now (Box 4)
  - Feminism (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1990s-2007 (Box 4)
  - Resumes and recommendation letters, 1980s-2000s (Box 4)
  - Newsclippings, 1980s-2000s (Box 4)
  - Tribe of Women, Connie Bickman, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Palestine materials, 1997 and undated (Box 5)
  - New Hanover Committee for Women, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Beijing Conference materials, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Resumes, 1970s-1980s (Box 5)
  - Duke Chapel sermon, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Newsclippings and awards, 1977-2001 (Box 5)
  - Photographs (Box 5)
    FRAGILE: Includes identification slips and post-it notes. Please use caution when handling.
  - State Normal Magazine, Greensboro, Nov. 1917 issue (Box 5)
  - Burnout Retreat materials (Box 5)
  - Beijing post-conference materials, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Beijing conference materials, 1999 (Box 5)
  - NC Council for Women materials, 1990s (Box 6)
  - National Women's Conference in Houston report, 1978 (Box 6)
    Includes inserts and some Beijing materials, 1995.
  - Newsclippings, 1980-2007 (Box 6)
  - Subject and conference files, 1970s-2008
    - Special projects and events (Box 6)
    - Corporate Responsibility Coordinating Group, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Sarah Weddington (Box 6)
    - Aging Without Apology workshop (Box 6)
    - Feminism (Box 6)
    - Seneca Falls, 150 years (Box 6)
  - Ephemera
    - United Methodist Women, NC Conference totebag (Box 6)
    - China-US Conference totebag (Box 6)
    - Medals and awards (Box 6)
    - Gargoyle figurine (from Duke?) (Box 6)
- Accession (2009-0150) and (2010-0131) 1970s-1997, 1 box
  The accession (2009-0150) (0.6 lin. ft.; 200 items; dated 1970s-1995) consists largely of scrapbooks from Roberts' conferences in the 1990s, including her trips to China, Singapore, and Malaysia as part of the Fourth Annual World Conference on Women, the NGO Forum on Women, and the World Methodist Conference, and her trip to Israel as part of an excavation course. Also included are materials from a filmstrip promoting the Equal Rights Amendment.
  Accession (2010-0131) (0.1 lin. ft.; 25 items; dated 1979-1997 and undated) comprises material primarily related to support for the Equal Rigths Amendment. Includes printed material, newspaper clippings, 15 color photographs, and an ERA necklace medalion.
  - Conference scrapbook: Methodist World Conference, Singapore, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook: Post-conference tour, Southeast Asia, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Conference scrapbook: NC Council for Women, NGO Forum, Beijing, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Conference folder and materials, NC Council for Women and NGO Forum, Beijing, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Conference photographs, NC Council for Women and NGO Forum, Beijing, 1995 (Box 7)
  - SEJ Excavation course scrapbook, Bathsaida, Israel, 1995 (Box 7)
  - What's all this about an ERA? filmstrip materials, including an audiocassette tape and film roll (Box 7)
  - Beijing news coverage videotape (Box 7)
  - Conference pins (Box 7)
  - ERA bracelet (Box 7)
  - Printed material, newspaper clippings, photographs, and ERA necklace medalion. (Box 7)
- Accession (2011-0108) and (2011-0123) 1811-2011 and undated, 1 folder
  Accession (2011-0108 and 2011-0123)(0.2 lin. ft.; 8 items; dated 1811-2011 and undated) includes a family deed regarding land in Craven County; a letter; printed items on women and religion, one of which is annotated by the donor; and a piece of ephemera with a quote from the ERA on the front and a Bible verse on the back.
  - Folder containing Accession (2011-0108) and (2011-0123) (Box 7)